our pform is a gopal bala chamberlain
will share the financial performance of
the company for the quarter and the year
ended march 31 202.
the industry registered a
gdpa growth of 11.1 percent for fi 22
as for public disclosures the combined
ratio of the industry was 119.2
for nine months fi 22 as compared to
110.4 for nine months fi-21
and the industry reported a loss of 4.05
billion rupees as against profit after
tax of 55.6 billion rupees for nine
months fi 22. 21.
further the overall combined ratio for
the private multi-line general insurance
was 112 112 in nine months fi-22 as
compared to 104.6 in nine month fi 21
the industry's solvency at nine months
fy 22 was worsened to
1.71 times as against 2.07 times at 9
months of fy 21.
so moving to the quarter under review
the industry delivered a mixed
performance
as for the data published by cm the new
vehicle sales witnessed epic growth of
private car segment
on the back of supply chain supply side
challenges
the two-wheeler segment remained far
from recovery while the commercial
vehicle segment has shown growth
supported by underlying demand
health insurance on the other hand
contributed significantly to the overall
industry growth in line with the
expectation and is now the largest
contributing segment to the gdp of the
industry
the commercial line witnessed robust
growth in sync with current market
environment coming to the business
impact for us the community has grown
it's grown
in line with the market growth of 12.7
percent this is excluding crops and
markets as against the lower growth that
we witnessed till nine months of fi-22
within the quarter the growth momentum
has increased each month and the company
has significantly outgrown the market in
the month of march 2022.
coming to the growth for key segments
during the quarter for motor the company
has grown faster than the industry and
we have now attained market leadership
in this segment
for the year
our investment in the retail health side
has started
to show results and has resulted in our
agency channel premium growth of 29.5
percent for the quarter
as indicated in our previous calls after
thousand retail health agency managers
to be added to our employee base we have
now onboarded 750 of them during this
fiscal and the balance 250 offers have
been made
we expect the growth to accelerate and
accelerate in the next few quarters as
the sales force starts getting
productive
the corporate agency channel including
vanquishers is back in the black with
overall growth of 19.4 percent
within this icsa bank distribution group
grew by 24.9
primarily driven by health indemnity sme
and motor business
and other distribution partners acquired
through the integration grew 15.9 during
the same period
our business source through our website
grew by 20
within this our health business grew by
travel grew by 130 percent and motor
grew by 10 percent
business source through strategic
alliance partners in the digital
ecosystem grew by 98.2
overall our digital solutions has
enabled us to increase our digital
revenues by up to 7.74 billion for the
current year which accounts to accounts
to 4.3 percent of our overall gdp
as for the commercial lines are
concerned we experience robust growth
driven by 17.8 growth in the sme segment
let me now give you an update on some of
our other key initiatives
on the integration i'm very happy to
share that as we speak isis lombard
stands as the second largest non-life
insurer in india
exactly as envisioned while evaluating
the scheme as a potential transaction
the integration enabled us to strengthen
our market leadership augment and
further strengthen our diverse
distribution channels the revenue and
operating operations energies the theory
plans are on track and gopal will talk
about this in detail in a segment
our ielts care app has surpassed 1.3
million downloads with successful
submission of
over one lakh thirty thousand claims and
over seventy thousand teleconsultation
requests
the recently added feature face can
helps users to keep a track of vitals
such as blood pressure hurt heart rate
respiration rate etc all without any
additional devices and from the comfort
and safety of one's home
i'll take care is built to be user
friendly and a continuous engagement
platform which is increasing our ability
to cross sales
we are also pleased to share with you
that we are the first large insurer to
move our entire core systems
onto the cloud this year
in our data center we had about 110
applications across 600 servers and
around 1 000 terabyte of data
moving our complete setup onto cloud has
given us some
immediate benefits including stability
availability and scalability
as such some of the investments that we
have made during the year in
distribution and technology is bearing
fruit and we expect to see momentum in
growth as we head into the next
financial year
we intend to continue with our expansion
across distribution digital technology
and claimed services towards this we
have planned additional investments in
the range of rupees 1 billion to rupees
1.5 billion during this year during the
coming year i will now request gopal to
take you through the financial numbers
for the recently concluded quarter
thanks bhagav and good evening to each
one of you i will now give you a brief
overview of the financial performance of
the company for quarter 4 and fi 20 2022
we have put up the results presentation
on our website you can access it as we
walk you through the performance numbers
the effects of the re-merging the
financials have been incorporated in the
form of opening network as on april 1
2021.
further the financials for the current
year represent numbers of the merged
entity and the comparative numbers for
the previous year in the financials
pertain to stand-alone isis lombard and
hence are not comparable
the company has enhanced disclosure
requirement of reserving triangles by
giving separate reserving triangles for
motor third party
and non-motor third-party lines of
businesses
this is in accordance with the
regulatory guidelines on public
disclosures which is applicable to all
the players in the market
you may refer to slide number 29 and 30
of the investor representation on the
reserving triangle disclosures
our gross direct premium income of the
company was at rupees 179.77 billion in
effect with 2022 as against rupees
140.03 billion in fbi 2021. the industry
reported a double-digit growth of 11.1
on a lower base for a similar period
our gdpr growth was primarily driven by
growth in preferred segments given that
our approach has always been growing
business sustainably
the fire segment gdpi was rupees 27.5
billion in fi 22 as against rupees 21.58
billion in fbi 21.
as indicated in our results presentation
the overall gdp of our property and
casualty segment was replaced 50.24
billion in fbi 22 as against
39.29 billion in fbi 21. on the retail
side of business gdp of the motor
segment was at rupees 82.8 billion in
fbi 22
as again should be 70.2 billion in fbi
2021.
to harness the potential of these
segments we have been expanding our
distribution network to increase
penetration entire three entire four
cities our agents which includes the
point of sale has increased to 88 539
as on march 31 2022 from
nine sixty nine as on december thirty
one twenty twenty one
the advanced premium numbers was rupees
thirty three point six eight billion
as at mars thirty one twenty twenty two
as against thirty four point five nine
billion as that thirty first december
twenty twenty one
resultantly combined ratio was 108.8
percent in fy2222
as against 99.8 percent in fbi 21 and
111 percent in nine months fbi 2022
combined ratio was 103.2 in quarter four
five twenty two as against hundred and
one point eight percent in quarter four
fy twenty one
and hundred and four point five percent
in quarter three five twenty two
our investment assets rose to rupees
387.86 billion at mass 31 2022
from rupees 374.54 billion at december
31 2021.
our investment leverage net of
borrowings was 4.23 times at mass 31
compared to 4.23 times at december 31
investment income was at risk 30 billion
in fy 22 as against rupees 21.96 billion
in fbi 21.
on a quarterly basis investment income
was would be 7.06 billion in quarter 4
at by 22. as against rupees five point
three seven billion in quarter four f by
twenty one
our capital gains was at rupees seven
point three eight billion in five twenty
two has against
rupees three point five nine billion in
fbi 2021
capital gains for quarter 4 fi 22 was at
rs 1.36 billion
as against rupees point six six billion
in quarter four f by twenty one
the successful integration of the team
was business of barthiaxia into the
company has led to optimization of our
organizational structure
rationalization of offices
efficiencies in claim settlement
practices and technology applications
this will result in an annualized
synergy benefits of rupees 2 billion
of which rupees point seven billion has
been realized in fy 2022.
our profit before tax was rupees 16.84
billion in fi-22 as against rupees 19.54
billion in fi-21
whereas pbt was rupees one billion in
quarter four five twenty two as again
should pays four point five billion in
quarter four f by twenty one
as explained above the company has seen
higher growth momentum in q4
fy 22 and within that in the month of
march 2022 due to the current accounting
norms this results in a printing of
sourcing costs
whereas the benefit of earned premium
will be realized over the policy period
consequently profit after tax was rupees
12.71 billion in fi 22 as against rupees
14.73 billion in fbi 21
whereas profit after tax studies rupees
3.13 billion in q4 fi 22 has again
should be 3.46 billion and q4 fi 21.
the board of directors of the company
has proposed a final dividend of rupees
5 per share for fi
2022. the payment is however subject to
approval of shareholders in the ensuing
and general meeting of the company the
overall dividend for f522 including
the proposed final dividend is rupees
nine per share
written on average equity was fourteen
point seven percent in fy twenty two as
against twenty one point seven percent
in fi twenty one the return on equity
for q4 fi twenty two was fourteen
percent as against eighteen point eight
percent in q4 f5 21
solvency ratio was at 2.46 times at mass
31 2022 as against 2.45 times at
december 31 2021 which continued to be
higher than the minimum regulatory
requirement of 1.5 times
as i conclude i would like to reiterate
that we continue to stay focused on
profitable growth
sustainable value creation and
safeguarding interest interest of
policyholders at all times
i would like to thank you all for
attending this earnings call and we will
be happy to take any specific questions
that you may have thank you
thank you very much we will now begin
the question and answer session
anyone who wishes to ask a question may
press rn1 on their touchstone telephone
if you wish to remove yourself from the
question queue you may press star into
participants are requested to use
handsets while asking a question
ladies and gentlemen we will wait for a
moment while the question q assembles
participants
you may press star in one to answer
questions
the first question is from the line of
shivani from clsa please go ahead
all right thank you for the opportunity
so a couple of questions i had i'll uh
probably just take two and then get back
in the queue uh first one is on the tp
hike rate uh that was announced and uh
what is the in what is your feedback on
how comfortable are you with the kind of
hike
uh that the regulator has proposed and
if you can help us get to an idea uh i
mean in spite of the hike i think given
that the car underlying car sales is
still weak if you can help us understand
how much proportion of your motor tt
book is private cars that would be the
first question second is on your uh
so just looking at your march 22 uh data
month the monthly data
so the uh
the uh
the trend in your moto tp book was quite
strong and it was uh stronger than the
industry for that matter so if you can
give me uh so if you can help us
understand that and lastly on the loss
ratios for fire it's uh come down quite
dramatically in this quarter so if you
can help us understand that please any
questions
um thanks
um so let me uh
take the questions
give the answer the same sequence so if
you look at the
pp rate hike
it's different across different segments
but the long term pp rates hike is
is a bit higher
overall at a portfolio level for the
industry if weighted average increase
comes to roughly about 3 odd percent
plus minus
you know honestly speaking given the
general inflation that we see
we would have
liked to see slightly higher rates in
certain categories
in certain certain categories we are
fine with the rate height that has been
given um so in aggregate maybe a little
bit higher would have been uh
appropriate is our view on this
when is it expected as of now the
understanding is that it will come
around me
uh so that's where we are on the tp uh
hike
uh in terms of the mix i'll ask gopal to
answer the next point on the on the
private side
yeah so uh sure as you can see uh so far
we we have given on this slide uh this
split of od and tp which is roughly
about 40.68 billion is zone damage and
about
42.12 billion is third party
within that 42.12 private car third
party will be about 13.49 billion
coming back to your question on on
growth i think what's uh happened as
we've been kind of
explaining for the last few quarters is
that
we took some calibrate call on uh
uh
kind of uh re-adjusting our portfolios
away from certain private car segments
given the pricing competition that we
saw on the private car and the website
and increasing uh
on the cv side again very calibrated
very selective calls
based on uh you know ground level
insights plus some experimentation that
we've been doing for the last three
years to
uh
to figure out if some of those books are
going to be uh
you know better risk for us
now when in retail when you cut down the
cut you know the
the number goes away immediately but to
build up it takes some time so i think
on the commercial side the growth
momentum is now picked up and what we've
been kind of uh indicating is that if
you look at our own portfolio mix unlike
the market where
out of the total motor book roughly 45
would be a commercial vehicle for us
that was in the teens maybe you know 15
to 17
that as we've been saying that should go
to roughly in the mid-20s
uh so that journey has now started uh we
will have to see if we can maintain the
momentum of growth of march but uh
clearly the
the increase in the market share of cv
is something that we expect going ahead
and your last question on fire loss
ratios share again i think uh i think
that's one segment where we keep talking
about saying that
a quarterly loss ratio may not
necessarily be reflective of the
underlying uh outcome of the performance
a better
number to look at will be more i would
say
financial year numbers in fact within
that
i mean there could be years where
because of let's say various large
losses or catastrophic years in fact
the loss ratio of that particular this
segment could get impacted
so hence
quarterly numbers may not necessarily
kind of reflect as i said the underlying
outcome look at more the annual numbers
for the fire part of the business
okay thank you
thank you
the next question is from the line of
abhishek saraf from
jefferies ahead
uh yeah thanks for the opportunity so i
just had a few following questions from
the earlier question last so so you
mentioned that in the cv we are looking
at a higher
mix in the uh so what is giving us
confidence uh in terms of maintaining or
containing the loss ratios and that if
you can just give us a few more details
in the kind of experiments that you have
run and uh please where are we deriving
this confidence from uh secondly if you
can help me understand i believe that we
have taken uh hikes in motor od segment
so what would be the
average quantum of hike that would we
would have taken and which kind of car
segment and
is it across the board that we have
taken me in the new uh or basically in
the sense that for new cars or is it
across the board for new and old cars i
have a few more questions after this
we'll uh just after if you can answer
this i'll follow up here yeah thanks
thank you so in terms of
uh i think we've been talking about what
we've uh the way we've uh handled this
again if you again reiterate the point
it is not as if we believe the whole tv
portfolio is
hardly turned uh viable or sustainable
or profitable
if you look at the overall industry mix
cv will be as i said between 45 to 50
percent we are not talking about going
anywhere we are near that number
now what we've been doing for the last
three years
again at various times we've talked
about this
is that based on ground level insights
based on some changes that we are seeing
both at in certain micro segments
certain markets
uh based on certain usage patterns or
accident patterns that are changing in
certain states or
even some amount of
you know the regulatory you know and the
compliance standards in some of these
markets
we
have been identifying some segments that
we believe are viable today than with
what they were in the in the past
and what we've been doing as a company
is that we've been taking small bits to
see you know writing small amounts of
business
uh reserving at a level where we believe
uh you know it is very very conservative
but allowing the team to write some of
those businesses to see what is the
experience that we have over the next
two to three years
some of those experiments have proved to
be in line with our expectations so
those are areas where we are scaling up
businesses
uh so so that's the confidence that we
are getting in terms of the uh the
segments of business now in terms of
and the approach that we are taking is
not just a loss issue of you you're not
looking at loss ratio you look at the
combined ratio in terms of sourcing cost
and loss ratio together and wherever
there is more uh viability that's where
we are taking those calls
in terms of uh
you know
in terms of
private cars the increases reasonably
across board there are one or two aims
which haven't agreed uh we are
discussing but most of the areas we've
taken price increases
thanks for that answer
just if you can help us understand
if you can share the
the quantum of hikes on an average that
we would have taken
it could be single regulation it's not
as if you've taken a huge hike it will
be a single digit
okay okay that's very helpful uh
secondly uh on
just notice that in the calamity losses
uh
our share of losses have actually gone
up in this year
so
is it only because of integration with
bharti extra or is there more to it
so if you can help me understand the
rs is our share of premium also have
gone up uh proportionately
in line with the losses as well
yeah so this was largely the cycle on
top that you're talking
[Music]
if you look at the last 10 12 cats our
share of losses being significantly
lower than our normal market share
uh in talking we had two of our
corporate exposures that got hit so it
was kind of a you know unfortunate
concentrated event not
uh as if there was a large impact across
gold so that's why we have a impact in
the docket because in you know in those
cases we're in the western market where
we have a slightly higher share than our
natural market share so when you look at
a you know let's say lost here that
we've got relative to the market here in
these markets they get lower
yeah thanks virgo that's very helpful
thanks a lot
thank you
the next question is from the line of
madhukar ladda from illara capital
please go ahead
hello
audible
yeah
yeah uh uh yeah thanks for for the
opportunity
um so
you know your od loss ratios for uh odi
and tpp and especially tp actually
uh for uh q4 have risen quite materially
and
if you look at
the
quarter by quarter trend there is quite
a bit of volatility
now
uh you know when we look into the future
uh how should we be thinking about it
should we be thinking more in terms of
you know exit rate will be uh more
appropriate for next year
or the
the the fuller rate as a base uh and so
what what sort of
how do you sort of project these things
or how do you look at it
so if you look at the water own damage
segment
i think to my mind uh when you look at
more the exit rates for if quarter four
is will be largely reflective of the
trend line that one would one could
potentially see so far as the way
forward is concerned and the reason why
we are saying is uh
in line with what we are discussed even
in our
earlier calls the thought process is to
try and see how we can get significantly
into
writing businesses which will be
relatively
uh driven in so far as more on
let's say high loss ratios and
relatively lower cost of sourcing late
businesses
that's the thought process that we have
in terms of increasingly building the
book
and that's the reason why i would say
quarter four on the motor own damage is
largely reflective of what one could
experience at least in so far as
the trend line for the future is
concerned having said that obviously we
continue to kind of uh micro segment the
portfolio to see which are the
segments which we want to
select and underwrite in terms of
building the overall book but the
thought process is in line with as i
build a book which is relatively
high lr and low experience in so far as
cost of sourcing is concerned
on the third party portfolio i think
maybe i think what you could
the full year numbers are largely
representative of what one could
experience in so far as
the way forward is concerned quarter
four specifically i think
in line with what we had
done in quarter four of last year if you
recollect i think there were those
supreme court judgments which had come
through
this is which we had to kind of revisit
all the
outstanding cases that we had as of the
previous year and we had to kind of
strengthen the reserving requirements
assuming the fact that we could expect
an increase in average claim payout
consequent to those judgments on the
outstanding cases as well
on the similar lines i think what we
have experienced over the last couple of
years which is for understandable
reasons that
the courts in india which is
predominantly where you get bulk of the
motor third party orders being received
that has not been functioning at full
force uh while we have started to see
particularly maybe quarter four we have
already seen things coming back but at
least over the last i would say uh three
to six quarters the courts have not
necessarily been functioning at uh full
swing what this does is obviously it
kind of starts to have an impact in so
far as a trend line of uh
settlements or cl or closures of cases
of third party that we would have done
related to the historical past
which would mean obviously given the
fact that there has been some lag in so
far as the extent of closures that we
would have normally seen which could
happen in the future period we obviously
have to kind of factor in for or maybe
build in an element of
further inflation assumption as a part
of our reserving book
particularly the element of interest
that we will have to add in so far as
our reserve reserving circumstance and
hence
uh the trend line for q4 on the third
party book will be more representative
of what one could expect so far as
future
trend line is concerned
uh
that's what i think for
q for even for tp
yeah and the other i think one should
also be mindful is i think given the
fact that we also strengthened
the reserving uh book of uh
the motor third party pool as you would
have seen in terms of the enhanced
disclosures
uh this element of increased uh interest
which we or inflation that we'll have to
build in as a part of the reserve has
obviously led in so far as the
earthquake motor pool book is concerned
we have obviously strengthened the
reserve however on aggregate basis
we have motor third party which is
actually reflecting a small amount of
reserve releases
got it got it
um
also then um just to add to what
effectively what we are looking at is
the combined rather than just the loss
ratio when we are selecting business
and the attempt is to bring the combined
uh more under control
not just look at the loss issue
right
uh i'm guessing the comparative
intensity is driving us
in this direction
um and and that's why they see you know
slightly probably lower commission
ratios and uh time expense ratios in
focus would that be right to say and
what would be like the trend for uh fi
so more than the company of computer
intensity is overall driving up the
overall combine for motor but if you
look at from a pure rv perspective
businesses which are high lr but low
expense tissue are better businesses
because expenses upfront
lr comes over the period
right right
and our expectation on how uh you know
like the integration the party and what
should be
our expense ratios and you know what
sort of expensive issues should we
expect in the fight
for like any guidance on that
number gopal has explained so very
difficult to put out a numbers uh
because i think on the one side as we
have put out what is what will be the
annualized energy numbers which we put
out as a part of the opening remarks
which is rough
sorry having said that i think what we
will continue to do when we look at
let's say fi 23 or maybe the year
thereafter we would want to continue to
kind of stay invested
in building some of our expansion plans
particularly what we have spoken about
on let's say on the health
agency distribution side we want to
continue to stay invested on building
our digital opportunities that we see
including the investments in technology
and claim service so to some extent i
think lastly what we would end up is
obviously we would we are pretty much on
track in order to kind of realize the
benefits of synergy but at the same time
you would want to kind of use some of
these to kind of
increase the opportunity that we see on
account of the renewed growth momentum
that we have seen for ourselves
so if you if you remember what we had
discussed when we did the
transaction we had said that for a
couple of years our combined issue will
be elevated and then it will start
coming down
if you see our combined ratio for this
quarter it's
related to the last two corners it's
already trending down
so that is an ongoing effort that you
will make to keep the combined ratio uh
under control now we also said that uh
as a strategy rather than bringing
combined down to 100 and delivering a 20
rv we want to keep on investing and
grow the book for a bit faster
consequently the other we may have come
down to the high teams
but eventually on your improvement and
combined that that should continue
understood understood and final question
uh i was reading the notes to accounts
uh there is a 65 crore payment
of gst uh under protest and an
additional agreement to pay 40 crores
can you explain that
and and you know what is this the result
of and
yeah the implications
yeah so these are a couple of matters
that as what we have put out
as a part of that disclosure on the
notes to accounts
as an insurance company we are entitled
to claim
input credit in so far as settlement of
motor claims related expenses are
concerned
both with respect to the arrangement
that we have either on a cashless or
whether on a reimbursement basis
in so far as the
gst department is concerned i think they
seem to kind of
allege that possibly we are not entitled
to claim certain inputs
with respect to some of those
motor claim related
expenses so that's one
the second is uh aspect is again with
respect to realization of as a part of
claim settlement again in the context of
motor portfolio we do kind of
end up
having certain element of
salvages
the view of the department is that on
that particular amount of salvage
amount that we end up realizing there
should be an element of gst
applicability on on the extent of
realizations that we have made
we have consulted
the
expert opinions as well as senior
councils on this in terms of the stand
that the company has taken both with
respect to the eligibility of input
credit or motor claims
as well as whether there will be any
element of applicability of gst so far
as salvage related
realizations are concerned the standard
of the company is pretty much
well found and
we and it is legally correct
uh so at this point of time obviously
that's the reason why the amount that of
65 crores is paid under protest and
another coffee cross is something that
we will uh we are committed to pay
at appropriate point of time in due
course we will be filing a refund for
getting this
amounts back but at this point of time
these amounts are largely
kind of paid under protest
what we clearly understand is obviously
this is something which is applicable
more at an industry level and hence to
that extent collectively we will the
standard of the industry is something
that we will work with and ensure that
we are able to get the rightful amount
that is due back to us
understood understood so this is an
industry phenomena so the tax department
is absolutely this is not specific to
isis
this both the issues are at an industry
level applicable to
almost all the players in the market
got it thanks thanks that's very helpful
thank you very much a request to all the
participants please restrict to two
questions for participants if time
common please come back in the question
q for a follow-up question
the next question is from the line of
players chain from motilal roswell
financial service please go ahead
good evening everyone uh
firstly uh could you talk about the
health claim ratios
on the retail side in particular in all
kinds of group health
how have they said in q4
and uh
are they back to pre-covert levels or
there are certain elements which are
still there with respect to covid and
how do you
see this going ahead i'll ask my second
question after that
so if you look at the split of
the health clock ratios which has been
given in the aggregate on the
presentation deck the breakup of that in
terms of
the employer employee portfolio or let's
say the corporate book that number for
quarter 3 was 93.1 that number for
quarter 4 is
95.3
and on the retail indemnity book
uh the loss ratios in quarter three was
about 65.7 and for quarter four that
number stands at about fifty seven point
six percent
yes uh
my question was uh you know while it has
and the repair is definitely has come up
and so this is more of a normalized
level now and we can presume it to be in
a similar trajectory going on right
so when you look at for example on the
corporate uh or let's say the employer
employee book we have always spoken
about saying that uh
typically particularly the large
corporates tends to kind of operate at a
loss ratio which could be ranging
anywhere between 95 to 100 anywhere
between that
and in so far as the relatively small
and mid corporate book is concerned they
generally tend to kind of operate on
again the employer employee part at
anywhere between 90 to 95 which is why
on a blended basis
i think one generally gets to see the
loss ratios which are relatively around
those 95 percent threshold however the
cost of acquisition with respect to
these businesses
particularly the last corporate tends to
be more direct and hence to that extent
on an aggregate basis on a combined
ratio book it
becomes viable for us to
underwrite having said that
i think over the last three or three
quarters we have been kind of talking
through particularly on the employer
employee book given the fact that we
have seen particularly this year the
impact of covet losses playing out we
have been affecting
clearly price increases
in so far as the renewal of the
portfolio is concerned
while we had indicated a price increase
in the range of 15 to 20 during our
quarter one earnings call but
subsequently as and when the actual
renewals have happened we have been able
to fight realizations which have been
slightly higher than that and
even with the increased price
realization we have been able to clearly
hold on to incur more than 90 percent of
the renewals in so far as
the employer employee or let's say the
corporate book is concerned
on the retail side again the thought
process is pretty much similar we
continue to keep looking at
the portfolio outcome in terms of what
is the desired loss ratio of the book
in general i think particularly the
indemnity book i mean depending on the
kind of book that you write the loss
ratios could range anywhere between i
would say 60 to 70 percent uh on a
steady state whereas the relative cost
of acquisition in the initial periods
would tend to be relatively higher given
the investments that we are making on
building distribution
so so that's that's what i would say in
so far as steady state
loss experiences are concerned both on
the corporate health or let's say the
retail indemnity book
okay
so the second question is more broad
level and a slightly longer term as well
so if you look at you know the efforts
that uh you know uh players like you all
have taken with regards to
uh
tech enable claim settlement processes
on the health side or on the motor side
several initiatives that have been taken
so we see that this
benefit the benefits of these efforts
will get more reflected in the pricing
coming down
or it would translate into more
combined ratio improvement uh so what
would be the strategy that is adopting
in in order to you know uh to take
benefits of these measures
so in terms of our long-term thought
process
this is just what you're talking about
is definitely correct but it's only one
element of what we are
how we are building this
so if you look at for example on our uh
claims um you know on the health side we
have launched that ai driven uh uh
authorization uh you know the ml engine
for settling uh
settling plays for uh corporates that's
currently running at a shade lower than
60 percent we believe that number will
keep increasing as we go along but the
approach is across multiple levels so
uh if you if you think about it uh you
know the entire approach with i'll take
care was to look at uh an engagement and
con
you know a continuum of care
approach with corporates and we believe
there are multiple advantages of that
beyond cost sale upsell engagement
renewals etc
even at the time of claims we
believe in the longer term we will see
some benefits so we are already
beginning to see that uh all you know
more than 40 percent of our corporate
client claims are coming even
reimbursement cases are coming through
the tap
we are
walking scheme in the past is when we
had moved the entire claim service
in-house back in 2008 nine
uh because we run the complete data and
do a lot of analytics around it we are
able to control uh we could at that
point in the control flows better on top
of it we build a lot of capability again
using artificial artificial intelligence
to
identify fraudulent claims better now as
we digitize the entire journey
you know the ability to run those
engines better becomes even uh you know
you know you have a ability to run those
engines even better so we are already
beginning to see some benefits in terms
of solving claims being managed better
lastly we believe if you can drive the
video consultation tele consultation
you know as a as a model to even control
unnecessary hospitalization that could
be additional benefit so
overall there is a
you know a very
comprehensive thought process in terms
of using technology to
both give better convenience and service
to customers and in the process improve
our relative
you know
loss costs for for the health claims
thank you
the next question is from the line of
sanket gora
from smart capital advisors please go
ahead
thank you for the opportunity uh
the price highs which we have taken in
motor od which we have said is largely
limited to the new business or we have
taken five by can be windows premium too
and then this just wanted to check
whether it is just limited to cars or on
a new private car uh some games
okay new private cost so so so
the control of price like we have taken
it does this will will it help in
improving the loss ratios which which
are currently 6822 and 73 in four
quarters so expected improvement in the
loss ratio because of this current price
size
uh we will have to see a few things uh
you know one of the things that we are
watching very closely is the uh claim
inflation because the input costs are
going up for everyone so there is a risk
that there won't be a claiming session
though till now in spite of the
inflation the team has managed it really
well uh in terms of controlling the
acs in you know average claim size
inflation
we are also you know driving a lot of
our
non oem source policies through our vpn
network that number has really gone up
this year so you know so we are trying
multiple strategies to prevent that from
going up but fact of the matter is that
we've seen significant increase in input
cost so there is a risk that there would
be an inflation because of that now if
that happens then we may not be able to
see that you know benefit
but
our sense is that at this point in time
where the private car ob goss issues are
it needs a price increase if so factory
whether whether we factor in the
equation or not so
uh so difficult to predict whether we
see improvement in loss ratio if the acs
implement doesn't happen the answer is
yes but we would have to guard against
is that
a industry phenomena that tries that you
are seeing across the page to happen
the reason i'm asking is that is the
potential risk for our market share loss
if you are the only guys who have taken
prices
we
don't think so because uh you know if
you see
the market share the recalibration that
we have to do we've effectively done
this year this is your only market share
this year has gone down largely for that
reason right because we felt that the
pricing was not adequate
where we are focusing on the effort that
we are building in terms of our digital
and agency channels uh you know maybe
some of the you know the uh
you know the slightly older segment we
remain reasonably confident about
holding onto a market share and an od
and something that we've been saying
that you know these two years have been
unusual because
you know people have benefited from
lockdowns at different times on the
motor portfolio right yeah and
traditionally whenever we see pricing
aggression it lasts for 12 18 months and
then things are you know correct back we
were talking about the pricing
correction
requirement even before the
pandemic right
so market was inaudible and ready for
that and then because of pandemic there
was people felt no need because of
frequency law you know came down we
believe the market will have to
rebalance and correct this year and we
are seeing the stress
we are
seeing that even with price increase
price uh correction that we are doing we
are holding on to our market share
you've seen our march numbers
uh and with the trendline events remains
that way
got it got it and and based based on the
tp business uh you said that the
meetings also contribution also cv to
the entire tp business want to even
reach to mid mid 25 in
so so this is wondering that have you
identified a particular product segment
where you can increase the market or
contribution to 10 percentage whether
whether uh is it like series or auto
rickshaws or kali please
which you have identified which will
drive this
uh increase in the contribution and and
so the loss ratios
yeah so it's not at that it's not just
that that level of segmentation is
significantly more granular
which obviously i don't want to get into
but we've looked at down to rto level
you know parameters take those calls not
just in terms of a product
obviously at no overarching level
but we've done a lot more deep analysis
on the ground
in terms of uh various factors we have
beyond uh categories
and on that basis we've taken this call
if you see our market share it's not a
10 shift that we're talking about as we
speak in the q3 number has already come
to close to 20 percent so we are talking
about that number going to mid teens
every 20's is
you know is not that big a
bigger stretch and as i said you know
when we started doing those experiments
about uh three years back
and we watched the data for the last
three years almost eighty eighty five
percent of the experiments have uh
worked out well for us
and that's where can we are kind of uh
uh expanding so yes a lot more micro
segmentation than those just the type of
vehicle that you're talking about
thank you
sorry to interrupt you so i'll request
you to come back in the question queue a
request to all the participants please
restrict to two questions per
participant if time permit please come
back in the question queue for a
follow-up question
the next question is from the land of
neeraj tushniwan from ubs securities
please go ahead
yeah i um
[Music]
uh
okay
but your voice is not coming very clear
may i requested to speak through the
handset
sure
is it better
yes
and uh how much battery would be
changing uh mix within the motorcycle
with higher tvs would that material be
different or with the pocketshare
identified
i mean uh we have grown substantially
higher in the uh march uh
we can expect going forward
but the i can would be
increasing losses so that would be kind
of you know magnifying each other might
be but uh but what incremental gains can
get through
you know we're not sure about your
question it is still not clear but if
you are asking because of the pp price
hike and the run rate of growth that we
see in march
if it's linked so if you look at the
increases that is being proposed we have
to wait for the final
increases that the increases for the
long term tv policy is is a bit higher
so there our new business should benefit
uh the approach on the
cv business is what we explained earlier
that
we are speaking of segments on a
combined ratio basis maybe the expense
ratio is a bit low but the loss ratio
could be a bit high but in aggregate our
combined ratio is what we are focusing
on in terms of building in a more
disciplined manner
got it not it and one more question uh
on motor od uh how do i obviously
explain but i wanted more
so as i said we think it should because
as it was explaining normally we've seen
over the last you know since
deterioration we've seen
these uh episodic uh you know aggression
in the in the private car in od segment
it does not sustain beyond you know 18
months 24 months this time it's been
closely you know three and a half years
so two of those years have been pandemic
so we believe it was also given driven
by the fact that during pandemic people
saved uh on claims cost uh so if you
look at the the industry we don't
believe people can sustain these kind of
pricing aggression for too long
uh but we'll have to see and as i said
you know when we are taking price
increases we are sensing that uh market
is also uh you know expecting something
like this
uh how much delta we can expect uh in
terms of growth coming in and what
timeline if at all
see you've seen a delta in the month of
march itself
uh we we remain reasonably confident of
sustaining that going ahead in fact as
we explained that you know when you hire
agency managers they come on board it
takes about two to three months for them
to even build their channels of agents
and then the agents start getting
productive so as of now we've only hired
about 750 the balance 250 you know are
expected to come in
and the initial signs in terms of the
hiring of agents that they've done if
you look at this month this quarter
uh you know we've had our added almost
eight thousand uh agents
for this quarter so it's it's picking up
the faction is high so there's no reason
to think that this uh gap in out
performance visually the industry should
should drop off in fact we should be
able to build momentum we are actually
very optimistic about that uh that
channel that we are building if you see
just the last quarter our agency channel
has grown by about 29.5
so i don't see a reason why it should be
lower than that for next year
thank you
the next question is from the line of
chaitan tucker from esk investment
managers please go ahead good evening
sir
as the two questions one is on the
health side just wanted to understand
how should we view combined over a
longer term
both for group and retail put together
and the mix that you're targeting
the second would be on the 775 crore
expense that is there in the shareholder
account which does not pertain to the
insurance business so what does that
exactly pertain to
yeah
the second one then
yeah let me explain the second one
i think uh so it's not that it's uh
those are expenses not related to the
insurance business that's more a
classification requirement in accordance
with the regulatory prescription
just to kind of explain this
i think the regulator has laid down
limits for all players in the market to
comply with limits on expenses of
management for the company as a whole
for isis lombard we are in compliance
with those limits for the at an
aggregate level having said that what
the regulator is also stipulated is
individual limits for some of the sub
segments of businesses within the
aggregate portfolio
and in case if in any of those sub
segments if the actual
based on the allocation of expenses that
have happened to those individual sub
segments in case if you exceed
then to that exchange from a
classification standpoint those amounts
are separately required to be given
on the face of the profit and loss
statement which is why you find
a large amount being reflected there but
equally when you possibly see
the revenue account statement there is a
counter entry there which i saw yeah
that is moving from shareholder to
policyholder and then moving back to the
policy yeah exactly so it's more a
classification requirement that is
stipulated in so far as regulatory
guidelines are concerned but as i said
for isis or lombard at an aggregate
level in accordance with the requirement
of regulation we are in compliance with
those limits of expenses so that is
helpful
and coming back to your second question
first question on on health look at this
stage even gopal explained the corporate
book it is a high loss ratio of business
in the 90s but the cost of sourcing is
low so
it stays in the you know just shade
above 100 100 105
uh we want to continue to ride that
business because
uh you know
that volume also helps us in terms of
the network and all the other aspects
that's corporate relationships plus we
are doing a lot of work with the i'll
take care app with corporates to see
what we can do in terms of cluster and
upsell so
that's something that we want to stay
invested but that's the kind of range
that we expect going ahead uh on the
retail we are investing and that's why
when i you know in my opening remarks i
talked about the overall investment that
we are making making in distribution and
and technology uh so retail indemnity
the the the health agency team that we
are scaling up obviously at this point
in time is reasonably highly combined
ratio uh
our sense is that you know it will take
over a couple of years for for us to see
that coming in line with our numbers
because we want to keep on investing
uh you know in that segment for uh
for some time at least for the next
couple of years is the next five years
out would 95 combine for health uh be a
number that we can work with so i
understand it will be a build up and
then things will scale up so just wanted
a more longer term picture
you know i always
i'm very worried about predicting five
year out numbers because none of us can
find five and out numbers
uh my sense is that of course the
combine would obviously come under much
better control
i do not believe that the number can be
a low 90s that some people articulate we
don't believe that that can sustain in
the indian markets you have to operate
at you know combined ratios which are
maybe closer to 100 not closer to 90.
okay that is helpful thank you so much
for this all the way
thank you
the next question is from the line of
trading from nippon indian mutual fund
please go ahead
yeah uh
hi so just one small uh clarification uh
did i hear you right saying that you
know you have diluted your rv
aspirations uh for growth
and hence uh the journey towards
handling combined ratio might not be
something which we would look for
yes what we've been saying is that we
would want to invest in some of these
segments of business largely digital and
health agency and we had said that
while we on the integrated basis on a
performance basis we were about 104 odd
number if you look at a 2020 performer
we had said that we would want to bring
it down closer to our normal target
number of 100 but we do want to invest a
bit uh in terms of scaling up these
businesses towards that if the rv comes
down below 20 we are okay it will be in
the high teams may not be 20 percent
but is this because of competitive
pressures that or or it is just a more
strategic
question or other sponsorship like what
has changed for you to you know
i remember earlier in our conversations
always the focus was on roe and
you know not diluting the combined
issues uh looks like uh there have been
some change in this
so bit of both honestly if you see the
on the health side it's more strategic
uh because of the investment if you
remember some of the conversations that
we've had that on the health indemnity
side we were building up some of the
capabilities
both in the outpatient opd product and
the ielts care app now that we've done
that we want to scale up the business so
that's and that's a strategic call
the rest of course given by current
context in the market the if the market
remains very aggressive then you know we
don't want to uh you know kind of lose
market share beyond the level
if our market connects you know there
will be an opportunity being combined
down under into our you know comfort
zone but at this point in time it's a
big bit of both you know
investment both in your agency and also
in digital to scale up the business for
the future
got it got it thanks thank you
thank you
the next question is from the line of
hidey from hightown securities please go
ahead
yeah thank you for giving me the
opportunity since out of the 88 000
agents that we have mentioned how many
would be selling health for us and also
in continuation with health uh icc bank
has started selling indemnity how much
of this can we kind of
like go up or what what can be the
growth path here and also is there any
update on hdfc bank and access selling
health for us or after working
partnership
so let me take you to the reverse order
so in terms of the
you know the key bank of partners that
we
got through the
acquisition we are very happy with the
way those partnerships are developing
as of now they are primarily focusing on
uh sme
and motor products but i'm sure there
will be opportunities to distribute
health in due course
um and if you see the growth of of that
channel while
the aggregate bank of partners of uh
baji as we said has grown at about 15.9
i think these two partners have grown
even faster so we are quite happy with
the way that that those channels are
shaping up
uh
coming to your
question on the uh bank business
look i think you know we've we've been
talking about the fact that we had a
base attack because of the decision of
the bank not to sell benefit policies
for you know from
q3 of the previous year and that had a
impact for our this year number for nine
months that and we've been saying that
that uh you know the that that base
effect will play out in this quarter
what the bank has decided to do is
rather selling benefit they are keen to
sell selling them nicky so you kind of
structure suitable products for the bank
and we launch it
i don't want to give any guidance on
whether the number will go up or not or
down because
uh at this point in time we've just
started selling some of these products
we'll see how it goes along and then we
will we will see what numbers we see but
at least the base uh
the negative base that we had of the
benefit book being there the previous
year and uh you know that business being
stocked this year that effect has now
gone
and your last question on
the number of uh
health agents within that number will be
about 6000
okay so last quarter we have added about
eight to ten thousand agents so not all
of them are obviously held
yeah we have three separate agency
channels one is motor one is health one
is sme of course we
you know we work across the channels and
try to cross them
but we have dedicated channels for the
three segments
okay
okay and so just ask if i can squeeze in
our advanced premium number for march is
lower than december so that means moto
tp growth is more towards cv is that
understanding correct or it is towards
renewable premiums
the combination of both
i think relatively
you're right to some extent given the
fact that let's say the contribution of
uh
cv in the overall motor growth is also
kind of uh higher in fight 22 compared
to f521 so that's obviously one
contributor
having said that i think equally if you
look at some of the older apps
what we had said even at the time when
these long-term policy guidelines had
come in we had said it will start to
kind of peak
maybe after attaining almost about three
to between the third and the fourth year
this number of advanced premium will
pretty much start to kind of peak
because you will obviously start to have
the incremental numbers on advanced
premium will be more reflective of what
kind of growth that we have that we will
achieve on the motor portfolio which is
what we have seen
in fi 20 21 22 this is the year where
it's been almost about three years since
the time the new
long-term guidelines had come so hence
that's the reason why you see a small
dip in so far as the advanced premium
numbers at 30 first matches that's uh
you know the other thing that we've been
saying that new vehicle sales both for
private car and two wheelers have been
quite low that has also happened
sir thank you that's it
thank you
next question is from the line of
nadeshine from investec please go ahead
uh thanks for the opportunity two
questions but firstly there's a lot of
comp in short companies are scaling
their costs
uh agency business
uh so how do we view this business do we
see it as a threat or opportunity for us
uh secondly uh in the new vehicle new
private cars segment have we uh have
been lost
how the market share trends in that
segment have we lost market share gain
market share in last one year and just
in the new private private car tech
the negotiation they get second question
first in the nine months we lost market
share uh that's why our you know if you
see our motor numbers were uh quite low
in the you know relatively lower in the
first nine months
this uh you know this quarter we have
not lost as much we've lost a little bit
in the private car side but made up in
the two-wheeler and the cv
uh it's on the quarter and our sense is
that even on private car the
recalibration or the portfolio at that
alignment that we wanted to do given the
pricing aggression with largely largely
behind us so we should we hope to see uh
you know market share even in private
car segment being held on
uh coming back to your first question on
insure tech look in
you know at this point in time we are
partnering with almost all of them
uh in terms of whether in the long term
it's uh it's positive or negative you
know there's one positive in terms of
them potentially expanding as of now
they're not expanding the market really
because they're
more playing like aggregators
aggregating existing agents under their
uh their uh umbrella but we hope that in
due course they will expand the market
and go and we are
at this point in time we are working
with all of them
on the post side we are not with the
digital aggregator but on this segment
we are working with them
sure okay thank you sir
thank you
the next question is from the line of
nation
from kodak securities please go ahead
hi am i audible
definition
yeah
my question actually pertains to the
last two slides of the presentation
and uh i think what you mentioned is
that based on the revised disclosures uh
you have split the reserving of you know
triangle disclosures between motor tp
and the others
now i think what we can see over here is
that the releases in the other segment
is higher than motor tp uh if i look at
you know i mean over the years
so how should one really be reading it
what is the interpretation of it is it
something
is concerned fundamentally there is no
change uh in terms of the process that
we follow uh for the current year
relative to let's say what approach we
have been following over the last
several years
and the approach is to kind of reserve
conservatively at source
and as and when each of this portfolio
kind of starts to develop in terms of
loss experiences
you will possibly see whether the
reserve estimates that we made at source
was adequate or not so adequate
in some of these lines the
conservativeism of reserving will start
to play out faster however in certain
long tail lines of businesses that will
obviously take a relatively longer time
for you to reflect
whether the reserves that we carried at
source were adequate or not
slide 29 and 30 the point that you made
other than motor third party lines of
businesses are predominantly
businesses which have a relatively
shorter tail in so far as claim
settlements is concerned which is why
the play out of the actual loss
experience tends to be faster and you
are able to kind of see relative to the
amount of reserves that we carry
you are able to see let's say small
amount of reserve releases however
in so far as the third party book is
concerned as i said that's a book which
is long tail
and obviously it takes a longer horizon
before which one can say whether the
amount of reserves that we have kind of
built in is appropriate or not
having said that if you look at the
information that gets put out whether it
is for motor third party or whether it
is for the other other lines of
businesses other than third party
the information is given for the last 10
years
and you can see over the last 10 year
cycles
even after 10 years of
development
both with respect to the motor third
party triangles that you see as well as
the other than motor third party
triangles
this is the loss development experiences
our approach to reserving has played out
to be conservative at source
and both of them reflect small amount of
reserve releases in the portfolio
and if i can add to what gopal said we
are actually very happy that this
disclosure has been mandated by the
regulator we've been asking for this
disclosure for a long long time
we were the first company to disclose
and now we are seeing more disclosures
it's not just the two
uh you know pool and aggregate there's
all the disclosures of uh now you know
tp business for the running book
and the non-degree business which is a
very good development
perfect thank you very much
thank you very much
ladies and gentlemen we will take that
as the last question
i now hand the conference mr vargas
gupta for closing comments
thank you thank you everyone for joining
and again you know if you have any other
separate questions feel free to reach
out we'll be happy to take them
separately thank you again thank you so
much take care and good night
thank you very much